Guide to the Dickason Papers, 1866-2012 MSS.172
Fales Library and Special Collections
Dickason Papers
1920-2012
Fales Library and Special Collections
Dickason, Jerry G. (Jerry Grove)
Dickason, Elly, 1940-
MSS.172
12.5 Linear Feet in 19 boxes
This collection is comprised of materials documenting Jerry G. Dickason's and Elly Dickason's affiliation with the Judson Memorial Church and its associated organizations, including materials related to the production of the book Remembering Judson House, which was published in 2000. These materials date between 1920 and 2012 and include correspondence, manuscripts, research notes, research materials, galley proofs, board minutes, photographs, newspaper clippings, transcripts of sermons, church bulletins, artwork, and media.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of materials documenting Jerry G. Dickason's and Elly Dickason's affiliation with the Judson Memorial Church and its associated organizations, including materials related to the production of the book Remembering Judson House, which was published in 2000. These materials date between 1920 and 2012 and include correspondence, manuscripts, research notes, research materials, galley proofs, board minutes, photographs, newspaper clippings, transcripts of sermons, church bulletins, artwork, and media.
Related Materials
Judson Memorial Church Archive (MSS.094)
Biographical / Historical
Jerry G. Dickason, a retired professor, and Elly Dickason, a long-time member of the Judson Church congregation, edited the book Remembering Judson House (Judson Memorial Church, 2000), a compilation of 48 interviews with people who lived or worked at Judson House.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into five series: Series I: Production Materials; Series II: Source Materials and Research; Series III: Administrative Materials Unrelated to "Remembering Judson House;" Series IV: Hot Spots Calendar (includes Production Materials), and Series V: 2016 Accretion.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Dickason Papers were initially donated to NYU in 2002. Accretions followed in 2007 and 2013. A third accretion was donated by Jerry G. Dickason in April 2016; the accession number associated with this gift is 2016.051.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual and born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records); Manuscripts; Calendars.; Audiocassettes.; Proofs (printed matter); Drawings; Sermons.; Church bulletins.; Clippings (information artifacts); Color photographs.; Judson Memorial Church (New York, N.Y.); Nute, Don; Dickason, Jerry G. (Jerry Grove); Dickason, Elly, 1940-; Covington, Jim; Knottenbelt, Maarten Jan, 1920-2004; Carmines, Al; Moody, Howard, 1921-2012
- Series I: Production Materials
  - Subseries A: Correspondence
    - Initial Correspondence and notes for Remembering Judson House, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Correspondence Following Publication of Remembering Judson House, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Review Copy Corespondence for Remembering Judson House, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Marvin Taylor regarding Deposit of Dickason Papers at Fales, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Bailey - Hendricks, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Holt - Oldenburg, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Ovitt - Yampolsky, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Manuscripts
    - Manuscripts by Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Benn - Garrard, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts by Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Goodman - Johnson, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Manuscripts by Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Kaprow - Oldenburg, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Manuscripts by Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Ortiz - Tungate (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Manuscripts by Contributors to Remembering Judson House: Wesselman - Yangas, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subseries C: Design Materials
    - Correspondence with Impressions, Compositor for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Impressions, Compositor for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Impressions, Compositor for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Text of Remembering Judson House Submitted to Impressions, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Text of Remembering Judson House Submitted to Impressions, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Text of Remembering Judson House Submitted to Impressions, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with Shirley Chetter, designer for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence with Quinn - Woodbine, Inc., Printer for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Final Pageproofs for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Final Pageproofs for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Remembering Judson House Mock-Ups (10), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Remembering Judson House Photocopies of Photo Album, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Uncorrected Image Proofs for Remembering Judson House, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Corrected Image Proofs for Remembering Judson House, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Images (photocopies) of Judson Health Center + Judson Gallery, 1920-1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Images (photocopies) not used for Remembering Judson House, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Images (color copies) of Judson House (interiors + exteriors), 1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Image Research for Remembering Judson House, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Final pageproofs for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Final pageproofs for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Proofs ("Blues") for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Proofs ("Blues") for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Permission for Remembering Judson House, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - ISBN and CIP information for Remembering Judson House, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Subseries D: Media
    Scope and Content
    Box 5 consists of moving image and audio; box 5a consists of computer disks. These items are originals: no access copies currently exist for resarcher use.
    - Governance Tape I, 04/09/1994; ID: 172.0001 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0001)
    - Governance Tape II, 04/09/1994; ID: 172.0002 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0002)
    - Governance Comm. Mtg, 06/07/1994; ID: 172.0003 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0003)
    - Governance Comm, Undated; ID: 172.0004 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0004)
    - Cong. Meeting, 05/17/1998; ID: 172.0005 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0005)
    - Judson Congregation Mtg., 11/08/1998; ID: 172.0006 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0006)
    - Judson Congregation Mtg., 12/6/1998; ID: 172.0007 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0007)
    - Congregational Meeting, 01/24/1999; ID: 172.0008 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0008)
    - Congregational Meeting, 01/24/1999; ID: 172.0009 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0009)
    - Judson Bd., 08/24/1998; ID: 172.0010 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0010)
    - Judson Board, 09/09/1998; ID: 172.0011 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0011)
    - Judson Board, 08/24/1998; ID: 172.0012 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0012)
    - Judson Board, 09/09/1998; ID: 172.0013 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0013)
    - Judson Bd, 01/6/1999; ID: 172.0014 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0014)
    - Judson Bd, 01/06/1999; ID: 172.0015 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0015)
    - Judson House Service Original, 07/11/0999; ID: 172.0016 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0016)
    - Judson House Service, 07/11/1999; ID: 172.0017 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0017)
    - Judson House Service Demo Tape, 07/11/1999; ID: 172.0018 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0018)
    - Greg Shunick 1, 04/19/1998; ID: 172.0019 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0019)
    - Greg Shunick 2, 04/19/1998; ID: 172.0020 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0020)
    - Jon Hendricks Interview Tape 1, 12/29/1998; ID: 172.0021 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0021)
    - Jon Hendricks Interview Tape 2, 12/29/1998; ID: 172.0022 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0022)
    - [Robt. Boy a Interview re 81 W. 3rd Street], 01/06/1999; ID: 172.0023 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0023)
    - Untitled, Undated; ID: 172.0024 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0024)
    - Untitled, Undated; ID: 172.0025 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0025)
    - Untitled, Undated; ID: 172.0026 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0026)
    - [Seyman Hacker], 04/01/1999; ID: 172.0027 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0027)
    - Roland Wiggeys, 06/22/1999; ID: 172.0028 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0028)
    - Interview with Tom Wesselmann, 12/03/1999; ID: 172.0029 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0029)
    - Judson Run Away [...] Interviews, 02/28/2000; ID: 172.0030 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0030)
    - Interview with [Claes Oldenbury] for Judson House Book, Undated; ID: 172.0031 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0031)
    - Untitled Tape 2, Undated; ID: 172.0032 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0032)
    - Untitled Tape 1, Undated; ID: 172.0033 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0033)
    - Untitled Tape 3, Undated; ID: 172.0034 (Box 5, Media ID: 172.0034)
    - Remembering Judson House Disk 1/4, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0001)
    - Remembering Judson House Disk 2/4, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0002)
    - Remembering Judson House Disk 3/4, Undated; ID: 172.3.0003 (Box 5A, Media ID: 172.3.0003)
    - Remembering Judson House Disk 4/4, Undated; ID: 172.3.0004 (Box 5A, Media ID: 172.3.0004)
    - Judson Hse Bk: Irene's Piece, Undated; ID: 172.3.0005 (Box 5A, Media ID: 172.3.0005)
    - Full text 2 NYC [Ffarrabes-end (Kurnitz Missing)] 2nd copy, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0006)
    - Untitled, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0007)
    - Judson Text, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0008)
    - Judson House Sample Pages, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0009)
    - [Scans Judson House 50' + 60's Judson Arts Part 1], Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0010)
    - Judson Photos, 01/08/1999 (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0011)
    - Judson Sunday School, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0012)
    - Medical [Center] Part 2 of 3, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0013)
    - The New York Times Picture Desk, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0014)
    - Untitled, Undated (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0015)
    - Dickason Post Script cx, 11/10/2000 (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0016)
    - Remembering Judson House Dickason Post Script, 10/24/00 (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0017)
    - Remembering Judson House Quark, fonts, art, 10/24/2000 (Box 5A, Disk ID: 172.3.0018)
- Series II: Source Materials & Research
  - Subseries A: Original Historic Materials
    - Original Historic Materials - Glass Lantern Slides - Judson Health Center Images (Box 6A, Box 6B)
    - Original Packaging for Glass Lantern Slides (Box 6C)
      General
      Box contains 5 small boxes and one larger box with "4 glass plates" written on it.
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Field Visit Havercia Danwelly, RN, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Dr. Eleanor Campbell, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center New Pictures, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Mayor Presents Scroll to Judson Founder, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Mrs. Brumfield RN with Mrs. Barbara Smyrnov, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Original Historic Materials - Judson Health Center, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Nutrition Class for "Future Homemakers", Undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Boys Cooking Class, Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Registration Desk, Undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center, Nurse Checks Height, Weight, + Temperature of Child, Undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Original Historic Materials - Photographic Print - Judson Health Center Children's Exam, Undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Black Scrapbook (Box 8)
    - The Judsonian, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - The Judsonian (Photocopy), Undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Judson Health Center - Original Documents, 1922-1942 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Measuring the Work of a Health Center (Eleanor A. Campbell), 1925 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - The Story of a Community Health Enterprise (Eleanor A. Campbell), 1928 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Scrapbook Clipping, Dr. Eleanor Campbell, Director of Judson Health Center Explaining Clinic to Visitors, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Pamphlets and Ephemera for Judson Health Center, 1925-1934 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Judson Studio, "Exodus", 1959 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Judson Studio, "Exodus", 1930-1960 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Judson Health Center copy of Eleanor A. Campbell's Will, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Report on Judson House Crisis Referral Unit Residence, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Fried Shoes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - A Voice in the Village; Howard Moody: Twenty Years of Washington Square, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Subseries B: General Source & Research Materials
    - Research Materials - Judson Health Center, Reports, Press, Releases, Correspondence, 1924-1962 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Research Materials - Judson Health Center, Board Meeting Minutes, Newspaper Articles, Reports, 1930-1943 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Research Materials - Judson Health Center, Press, Articles, Radio Reports, Reports, 1942-1962 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Research Materials - Judson House (New York Historical Society), 1998 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Research Materials - Judson Health Center - Information New York City District Health Administration, 1866-1938 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Research Materials - Judson Health Center, Copies of Booklets on Health Center, 1922-1928 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Research Materials - Eleanor A. Campbell/Judson Health Center, 1926-1951 (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - Research Materials - Anderson and Milbank Families/Judson Health Center (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Research Materials for Judson Gallery, 1960-1967 (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Research Materials - Judson House, 1951-1999 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - "Judson Health Center, 1920-1950" 3 Drafts by Jerry Dickason, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - [Brief History of the Judson Health Center], Undated (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Research Matrials - Judson Student House, 1948-1961 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - Judson Memorial Church Publications, 1990-2000 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Miscellaneous Pamphlets - "The Judson House Project," Off Limits, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Peter Maavman's Sermons, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Miscellaneous notes + bulletins to Judson Memorial Church Congregation, 1982-1993, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - Miscellaneous Color Pictures - Judson Garden + Tom Wesselmann, Jeremy Dickason, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Miscellaneous Pictures - Judson House Watching Negatives and Contact Sheet, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Miscellaneous Contact Sheet + Negatives - Judson House Matching 4x6 Prints, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Various Newspapers (Box 12)
- Series III: Administrative Materials Unrelated to "Remembering Judson House"
  - Board Meeting Minutes, Financial Report, Commission on Judson's Financial Future, Jan. - Dec. 1997 (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Board Meeting Minutes and Notes, Feb. - July 1999 (Box 13, Folder 82)
  - Board Meeting Minutes and Notes, Feb. - April 2000 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - Judson Board Meeting Minutes and Notes, Feb. - May 1998 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Judson Board Meeting and Notes, May - Sept. 1998 (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Judson House Board Meetings, Correspondence, Sept. - Nov. 1998 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - Judson Board Meetings, Correspondence, Nov. 1998 - Jan. 1999 (Box 14, Folder 87)
  - Board Meeting - Minutes, Dec. 1998 - Dec. 1999 (Box 14, Folder 88)
  - Board Meeting/Congregational Meeting Minutes and Notes, Oct. 1999 - June 2000 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - Board Meeting, April - Oct. 1999 (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - Board Meeting, Oct. - Nov. 1999 (Box 14, Folder 91)
  - Board Meeting, Dec. 1999 - Feb. 2000 (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - Board Meeting, May - Dec. 2000 (Box 14, Folder 93)
- Series IV: Hot Spots Calendar (Includes Production Materials)
  - Personnel Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - Personnel Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  - Personnel Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 96)
  - Personnel Committee - Confidentiality Articles, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 97)
  - Structures and Governance Committee Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 16, Folder 98)
  - Structures and Governance Committee, By-Lines, Mar. - Sept. 1994 (Box 16, Folder 99)
  - Structures and Governance Committee Correspondence, Mar. - Nov. 1994 (Box 16, Folder 100)
  - Structures and Governance Committee, May - Aug. 1994 (Box 16, Folder 101)
  - Structures and Governance Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - Structures and Governance Evaluation, June - Sept. 1998 (1) (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - Structures and Governance Evaluation, Jun. - Sep. 1998 (2) (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - Congregational Meeting, Jan. 1999 (Box 17, Folder 106)
  - Structures and Governance Evaluation, Nov. - Dec. 1998 (Box 16, Folder 105)
  - Congregational Meeting, Feb. - March 1999 (Box 17, Folder 107)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Don Nute Memorial Materials, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 108)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Calendar, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 109)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Drawing Paper, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 110)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for January, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 111)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for February, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 112)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for March, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 113)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for April, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 114)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for May, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 115)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for June, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for July, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for August, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 118)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for September, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 119)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for October, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 120)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for November, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 121)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Drawing for December, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 122)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Artwork (not included in calendar), 1978 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Hot Spots Calendar - Original Artwork (not included in calendar), 1978 (Box 18, Folder 124)
- 2016 Accretion
  Arrangement
  This accretion has not been arranged by an archivist; materials are arranged in the order in which they were received by the donor.
  Scope and Contents
  The accretion consists of materials that date between 1969 and 2012 with the bulk of the materials dating between the early 1970s and the early 1990s. Within the accretion are transcripts of sermons (including one by Elly Dickason), Judson Memorial Church bulletins, photographs used in Remembering Judson House, as well as memorial materials about the passings of composer Al Carmines and Minister Howard R. Moody. Also included in the accretion are materials about Dickason's and former Judson employee Jim Covington's involvement with the New York Center for Men (1983-1984), as well as a file about the research of anti-war activist Maarten Knottenbelt (1982-1989).
  - Judson House Book, 1972, 2001, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Judson Sunday Bulletins, 1971-1992 (Box 19, Folder 2-4)
  - Judson Sermons, 1969-1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The New York Center for Men, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Knottenbelt, Maarten, 1982, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Carmines, Al -- Obituary, 2005-2006 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Carmines, Al -- Oratories, 1976-1977, 1990, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Moody, Howard R., 1990, 2004, 2012, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Dickason, Elly -- Sermon on Illness, 1992-07-26 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Judson Service, 1994-09-04 (Box 19, Folder 12)